# Ralfi Salhon

# Senior Front-End Engineer

Portfolio: https://ralfi.dev
Contact: ralfisalhon@gmail.com
Github://ralfisalhon • LinkedIn://ralfisalhon

### **About Me**

Passionate software engineer interested in the field from as early as 13 years old. Experienced in working with engineers who have a collective goal of releasing high quality software. I seek to surround myself with people who like to teach and to learn from each other. I also am a;

• Classical Pianist • Swimmer • Video Editor • Game Designer

Hackathon Enthusiast

• World's Fastest Smartphone Typer (2019)

### **Work Experience**

Talos Full-Time, London, UK

Jun 2020 - Present

Senior Front-End Engineer • Jan 2024 // Software Engineer II • Jan 2022 // Software Engineer • Jun 2020

React.js, TypeScript, CSS

- Contributed to the growth of Talos from a 10-member team to over 130 employees, actively involved in all aspects of product development.
- Developed high-performance web components using React.js and TypeScript, implemented end-to-end testing with Jest and Cypress, and automated deployment pipelines with GitHub Actions, ensuring efficient and reliable software delivery.
- Created detailed monitoring panels for Talos's institutional partners, enabling effective order lifecycle management; regularly performed performance analysis and contributed to architecture calls to ensure optimal system performance.
- Organized an in-house AI hackathon with 78% company attendance, partnering with Google to pilot and evaluate their unreleased AI tools, leading
  to significant advancements in our AI initiatives.
- Contributed to the hiring of front-end interns by creating interview questions, evaluating candidates, and ensuring we onboard top talent.
- Fostered team engagement and company culture by hosting weekly company game nights.

JumboCode Part-Time, Massachussets, US

Jan 2020 - May 2020

Front-End Engineer

React.js, Node.js, Firebase, Heroku

- Implemented interactive features by translating UX wireframes and mockups using React.js, HTML/CSS, and JavaScript, enhancing user experience.
- Standardized components with a mobile-friendly approach, ensuring compatibility and optimal performance across various devices.

**Insider** Internship, Istanbul, Turkey

Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

Mobile Development Intern

React Native, React.js, Redux, Python

- Improved the reliability of the Insider iOS and Android SDK by implementing new geolocation and push notification algorithms.
- Developed and documented "iGurme", an e-commerce app which integrates all the features of Insider's enterprise level SDK. iGurme is currently used during sales and pitch meetings to promote Insider's new SDK features for both iOS and Android devices in over a dozen countries.

### **Education**

**Tufts University**, Massachussets, US
Bachelor of Science in Computer Science
GPA: 3.59/4.0

On Campus Employment, Teaching Assistant

Computation Theory: Course on the models of computation - Turing machines, pushdown automata, and finite automata.
 Computer System Security: Network-based computer security course. (Python, JavaScript, Linux)
 Game Design: Ground-up game design and development course. (Unity, C#, Photoshop, Maya)
 Web Programming: Full-stack web development course. (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, MongoDB)
 Spring 2020

University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong. Tufts University study abroad program with focus on music and history.

Spring 2019

#### Skills

**Libraries and Frameworks**: React.js • React Native • Node.js • Express • Firebase • Cypress • RxJS • Styled-Components • Redux **Languages and Tools**: TypeScript • JavaScript • HTML • CSS • Python • C++ • C • Heroku • MongoDB • Xcode • Git • VSCode **Design Software**: Illustrator • Photoshop • Figma • After Effects • Final Cut Pro • PyxelEdit

# **Personal Projects**

Most of my projects are open-sourced, I'm also always working on more. • Github://ralfisalhon

Talos Badges	Digital badge collection and showcase for Talos employees - Web app	<u>talosbadges.com</u>	Jan 2024 - Apr 2024
TuneWise	Music centered mobile party game - Web app	tunewise.netlify.app	Oct 2019 - Dec 2019
Jamblr	Music discovery and playlist creation platform - iOS app	apple.co/2MMTKtR	Oct 2018 - May 2019
Coverlove	Cover art maker for Spotify playlists - iOS app	apple.co/3oXbPNb	Feb 2019 - Mar 2019
<b>Red or Blue</b>	Strategy puzzle platformer game with controller support - Mac/Windows	bit.ly/redorbluegame	Sep 2017 - Jan 2018